An epic of miniature proportions.
A Bug's Life is a family, animation, adventure film directed by John Lasseter.
On behalf of "oppressed bugs everywhere," an inventive ant named Flik hires a troupe of warrior bugs to defend
his bustling colony from a horde of freeloading grasshoppers led by the evil-minded Hopper.
Flik (voice), played by Dave Foley.
Hopper (voice), played by Kevin Spacey.
Atta (voice), played by Julia Louis-Dreyfus.
Dot (voice), played by Hayden Panettiere.
Queen (voice), played by Phyllis Diller.
Molt (voice), played by Richard Kind.
A Bug's Life (stylized in all lowercase) is a 1998 American animated comedy film
produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It was directed by John Lasseter, written by Andrew Stanton, Donald McEnery, and Bob Shaw, from a story conceived by Lasseter,
Stanton, and Joe Ranft, and stars the voices of Dave Foley, Kevin Spacey, Julia Louis-Dreyfus, and Hayden Panettiere.
In the film, a misfit anthropomorphic ant named Flik looks for "tough warriors" to save
his ant colony from a protection racket run by a gang of grasshoppers.
However, the "warriors" he brings back are a troupe of Circus Bugs.
The film's plot was initially inspired by Aesop's
fable The Ant and the Grasshopper.
Production on A Bug's Life began shortly after the release of Toy Story in 1995.
The ants in the film were redesigned to be more appealing, and Pixar's
animation unit employed technical innovations in computer animation.
Randy Newman composed the music for the film.
During production, a controversial public feud erupted between Steve Jobs and Lasseter of Pixar and DreamWorks co-founder
Jeffrey Katzenberg due to the parallel production of his similar film Antz, which was released the month prior.
A Bug's Life premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on November
14, 1998, and was released in the United States on November 25.
It received positive reviews for its animation, story, humor, and voice acting.
It became a commercial success, having grossed $363 million at the box office.
It was the first film to be digitally transferred frame-by-frame and released
on DVD, and has been released multiple times on home video.
The film explores themes of fight, circus, winter, ant-hill, ant.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.